A Guide to the Ralph W. Cummings, Jr. papers FA116
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ralph W. Cummings, Jr. papers
1941-2016
Rockefeller Archive Center
Cummings, Ralph Waldo
FA116
8.49 Cubic Feet 17 letter document containers, two legal document containers, and one half-sized letter document container
Biographical / Historical
Ralph Waldo Cummings, Jr. was born on July 20, 1938, to parents Ralph Waldo Cummings, Sr. and Mary Parrish Cummings. He earned an AB with honors in Economics from the University of North Carolina in 1960 and went on to pursue post-graduate study at the Delhi School of Economics, Delhi University, on a Fulbright Scholarship from 1963-1964. He earned a PhD in Economics from the University of Michigan in 1965. His dissertation was titled The Structure and Functioning of the Indian Wheat Market, with Special Reference to Khanna, Punjab, 1956-1957 through 1963-1964. After graduating, Cummings started working as a Professor of Economics at the University of Illinois, Urbana, from 1965-1967 and 1969-1970. Cummings also served as a Lecturer in Public and International Affairs in 1976 and a Fellow from 1982-1983 at the Woodrow Wilson School at Yale University.
Cummings held a variety of leadership roles in international aid organizations. He served as Assistant Director of the Midwest Universities Consortium for International Activities (MUCIA) from 1966-1967, Chief of the Agricultural Economics Division of the Office of Agricultural Development for the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) in India from 1967-1969, Consultant to the Bureau for Near East and South Asia for USAID in 1970, Advisor in Agricultural Economics for the Harvard Advisory Group working with BAPPENAS, the National Development Planning Agency in Indonesia, from 1970-1972, and served as an Agricultural Economist for The Rockefeller Foundation from 1972-1982. Cummings started working as an Agricultural Economist for the US Agency for International Development in 1982 and held that position for more than 20 years.
Cummings was a member of the International Committee for American Agricultural Economics Association and a member of The Land Advisory Board for Walt Disney World's Epcot. Cummings authored numerous articles and books related to world hunger and agricultural activities in developing nations, including To Feed This World: The Challenge and the Strategy with Sterling Wortman, Policy Planning for Agricultural Development with S. K. Ray and Robert Herdt, and From Parastatals to Private Trade: Lessons from Asian Agriculture with Shahidur Rashid and Ashok Gulati.
Arrangement
The Ralph W. Cummings, Jr. papers are arranged into two series: 1. Professional Papers, 1958-2016 2. Cummings Family Files, 1941-2002
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist. When requesting to view audiovisual material, please refer to the Title and the AV Number (example: AV 1916). Researchers are asked to check the "Restrictions" note for each Title. If a Title does not currently have an access copy, please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2017 by Ralph W. Cummings, Jr. and ingested by RAC as Accession 2017:025.
Related Materials
For more information regarding Ralph W. Cummings, Sr. refer to the Ralph W. Cummings Papers, 1840-2001 held by the North Carolina State University Archives.
Scope and Contents
The Ralph W. Cummings, Jr. papers consist of published and unpublished manuscripts, reports, photographs, realia, and correspondence related to Cummings' work to eradicate world hunger and spur agricultural activities in developing nations, particularly in his roles as Agricultural Economist with the Rockefeller Foundation and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID).
The collection also contains Cummings family papers, including academic files and awards presented to Cummings' father, Ralph W. Cummings, Sr., and clippings and memorials to Cummings' mother, Mary Parrish Cummings.
Separated Materials
Special format items have been separated from the body of the collection and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
Rockefeller Foundation; Agriculture -- Economic aspects; Food supply -- Developing countries; Agriculture -- Developing world; Agriculture -- India; Indonesia
- Professional Papers, 1958-2016; 1
  - To Feed This World (TFTW) - Letters of Acknowledgement - A-H, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - To Feed This World (TFTW) - Letters of Acknowledgement - H-Z, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - To Feed This World (TFTW) - Reviews and Clippings, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - To Feed This World (TFTW) - Reviews, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - To Feed This World (TFTW) - Clippings, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - To Feed This World (TFTW) - Reviews, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - To Feed This World (TFTW) - Reviews and Comments, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Johns Hopkins University Press Contract, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Scope and Contents
    To Feed This World
  - Sterling Wortman, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conflicting Views on the World Food Production, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Books - Responses, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Poverty in India, V. W. Dandekar and Nilakantha Rath, 1971 January (Box 3, Folder 38)
    Ford Foundation Report
  - Agricultural Assistance Sources, International Agricultural Development Service (IADS), 1979 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Agricultural Assistance Sources, International Agricultural Development Service (IADS), 1980, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 40-41)
  - Methods for Diagnosing Research System Constraints and Assessing the Impact of Agricultural Research, Volume 1: Diagnosing Agricultural Research System Constraints, International Service for National Agricultural Research (ISNAR), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    Contains "Agricultural Technology Management: Draft Guidelines" by Ralph Cummings, Jr.
  - Pricing Efficiency in the Indian Wheat Market, Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - From Parastatals to Private Trade: Lessons from Asian Agriculture, Edited by Shahidur Rashid, Ashok Gulati and Ralph Cummings Jr, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Beyond the Bottom Line by Sterling Wortman, Edited by Ralph Cummings, Jr, The Rockefeller Foundation, undated (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Buffer Stocks, Reprint, Ralph Cummings, Jr, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Indian Journal of Agricultural Economics, Volume 36, Number 3, 1981 July-September (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - World Hunger: Its Effect, Its Dimension, Its Alleviation: Four Lectures Presented at a Symposium on World Hunger, North Carolina Agricultural and Technical State University, 1981 October 29 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - The State of Present and Expected Agricultural Research and Technology, Working Papers for Rockefeller Foundation, Food Crops in the Low-Income Countries, Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, 1976 May (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - BioScience: Vol. 41 No. 11, 1991 December (Box 5, Folder 50)
    Contains Rountables: Reverse technology flow as a key to future world and US agriculture, p 775
  - Reprints, 1986-1991 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    1. Development Assistance and Exports: The Case of the United States (2 copies), 2. International Capital Markets and Development Funds for Agriculture: Discussion, 3. Land Clearing and Development in the Tropics, 4. Reverse technology flow as a key to future world and US agriculture
  - Horizons, Agency for International Development (AID), 1983 October (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Agency for International Development (AID) Strategy Paper for Food and Agriculture Development Assistance, 1983 September-November (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Reports and Presentations, 1977-1981 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    1. Seminar Report: Minimum Information Systems for Agricultural Development in Low-Income Countries (2 copies), 2. Workshop on Linkages Between Agricultural Research and Farmers in Developing Countries, 3. Annex: Examples of What US Agriculture Owes to the Developing Countries, 4. A Strategy for Rural Development
  - Indonesian Agricultural Research & Development Journal - Volume 2, Number 2, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Plan for Supporting Agricultural Research and Faculties of Agriculture in Africa, Agency for International Development (AID), 1985 May (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Targets for Agricultural Development in Botswana, Kristian Oland, Hoyt Alverson and Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Agricultural Development Indicators: Statistical Comparisons of 139 Developing Countries, International Agricultural Development Service (IADS), 1981 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Agricultural Development Indicators: A Statistical Handbook, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - The Hunger Project Newspaper: A Shift in the Wind, 4, 1979 February (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Ohio's Challenges, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Sustainable Food Production Workshop: Policy Options to Promote Environmental Technologies, Beth E. Lachman, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Report: Global Consultation on Agricultural Extension, Food and Agricultural Organization of the United Nations, Rome, 1989 December 4-8 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Paths to Sustainable Food Production: Policy Options to Promote Environmental Technologies - International Perspective, undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Author! Author!: A Directory of Princeton Area Authors, 1961-1986 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - To Feed This World: The Challenge and the Strategy, Sterling Wortman and Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, Hardcover inscribed by Sterling Wortman, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - A Note on To Feed This World, 1978-1981 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - To Feed This World: The Challenge and the Strategy, Sterling Wortman and Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, Paperback, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - To Feed This World: The Challenge and the Strategy, Sterling Wortman and Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, Promise of Tomorrow Hardcover, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Policy Planning for Urban Development, Susanta K. Ray, Ralph W. Cummings, Jr and Robert W. Herdt, undated (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Strategi Untuk Menatasi Kelaparan Dunia (Strategies for Addressing World Hunger), Sterling Wortman and Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, undated (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Para Alimentar Este Mundo: El Desafio y la Estrategia (To Feed This World: The Challenge and Strategy), Sterling Wortman and Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Policy Planning for Agricultural Development, Susanta K. Ray, Ralph W. Cummings, Jr and Robert W. Herdt, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - From Parastatals to Private Trade: Lessons from Asian Agriculture, Edited by Shahidur Rashid, Ashok Gulati and Ralph Cummings, Jr, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Agricultural Diversification and Smallholders in South Asia, Editors PK Joshi, Ashok Gulati, and Ralph Cummings, Jr, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Changing Contours of Asian Agriculture: Policies, Performance, and Challenges, Essays in Honour of Professor V. S. Vyas, Editors Surjut Singh and V. Ratna Reddy, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Land Clearing and Development in the Tropics, Edited by R. Lal, P. A. Sanchez and R. W. Cummings, Jr, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - US Bureau of the Census - Ackley on Growth Theorem, 1958-1961 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - US Bureau of the Census, 1960-1961 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Who's Who in the Southwest, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - The Structure and Functioning of the Indian Wheat Market, with Special Reference to Khanna, Punjab, 1956-1957 through 1963-1964, Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    PhD dissertation, University of Michigan
  - Conference on Punjab Studies, University of Missouri, 1967 May 4-6 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Review of Rosen and Hanson, 1967 May (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Government Policy to Promote Food Self-Sufficiency in India, S.C. Mathur, 1967 October 20 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Wheat Pricing, The American Journal of Agricultural Economics (AJAE), 1968 August (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - New Agricultural Strategy Revisited, Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, Robert W. Herdt, and S. K. Ray, 1968 October 26 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Annex D - Food Production, US Agency for International Development (USAID), 1968 August (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - The New Agricultural Strategy, Economic and Political Weekly, 1969 March (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Weather and Technology, Economic and Political Weekly, 1969 September (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Vyas Review, Significance of the New Strategy of Agricultural Development for Small Farmers, 1970 January (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - US Export Potentials and the Green Revolution, Iowa State University, 1970 January 29 (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Long Range Agricultural Adjustment Analysis, 1971 January (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - Indonesia Papers, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Indonesia, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Illinois, 1962-1970 (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - India, 1966-1969 (Box 9, Folder 96)
    - P.L. 480 grant signing, New Delhi, photographs, undated; 2017:025:009 (Box 20, Folder 232)
  - Indonesia Development Planning Agency Luncheon photographs, 1972 June 2; 2017:025:010 (Box 20, Folder 233)
  - Agriculture Sector Studies/Agency for International Development (AID), 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - Agency for International Development (AID) - Country Field Submission Annex F, India FY 1971, 1969 September (Box 10, Folder 98-99)
  - Indonesia - photographs, 1989; 2017:025:015 (Box 20, Folder 234)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Agricultural Sciences Staff Seminar Group Photo, Williamsburg, Virginia, 1979 November; 2017:025:016 (Box 20, Folder 235)
  - 2008 Rockefeller Foundation Reunion, Cornell University, 2008 June 24-26 (Box 10, Folder 100)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Reunion Group Photograph, 2008; 2017:025:017 (Box 20, Folder 236)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Reunion 2000, Group Photograph, San Antonio, Texas, 2017:025:018 (Box 20, Folder 237)
  - Reviews of Policy Book, 1981-1987 (Box 10, Folder 101)
  - Colloque Sur La Liaison Entre La Recherche Agricole Et L'Utilisateur Dans Les Pays En Development, 1981 July 9-16 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1970-2009 (Box 10, Folder 103-105)
    Conquest of Hunger Program, Clippings, John Hilton Knowles Memorial Service, Correspondence related to joining the field staff of the Rockefeller Foundation
    - Untitled photographs, undated; 2017:025:019 (Box 20, Folder 238)
    - International Agricultural Development Service (IADS) - A Memento of the Bellagio Workshop on Defined Areas photographs, undated; 2017:025:020 (Box 20, Folder 239)
    - Untitled photographs, undated; 2017:025:021 (Box 20, Folder 240)
      Hunters and group with poached wild cat
  - Princeton High School, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Princeton Author's Day, 1979-1982 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Princeton University Teaching, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Walt Disney World - Epcot, 1976-1993 (Box 10, Folder 109-113)
    Correspondence with imagineers and Kraft, Inc. regarding The Land at Epcot, holiday cards, invitations and pamphlets regarding the 1982 opening of Epcot Center, 1983 Harvest of the Future Seminar, 1983 Hugh O'Brian Youth Foundation International Leadership Seminar, The Land Advisory Board Meeting Agendas, Spaceship Earth Gala pamphlet, Ticket for the grand opening of the The World Showcase Festival Program, Correspondence regarding the opening of The Land, and Epcot Future Technology Conference materials
    - Florida Canoe Trip, 1978; 2017:025:022 (Box 20, Folder 241)
  - Correspondence, etc, India book, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 114)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Plan Puebla Review, 1974 January 29 (Box 11, Folder 115)
  - Comment on Evenson paper, 1973 September (Box 11, Folder 116)
  - Seminar on World Food Production, 1974 February-March (Box 11, Folder 117)
  - Ceres: Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO), 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 118)
  - World Food Projections, 1974 August 15 (Box 11, Folder 119)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Food Production and Energy Dilemma, 1974 August (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - Trustees - Prospects for Meeting World Food Needs, Draft, 1974 December 12 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - World Food Conference, 1974 October 22 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Concluding Comments, American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1975 January 29 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - Midwest Universities Consortium for International Assistance (MUCIA) - Indonesia Seminar, University of Illinois, Urbana, 1975 January 24 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - Food Production - A World Perspective - Association of Caribbean Universities and Research Institutions (ACURI), 1975 February 7 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Prospects for Meeting World Food Needs, Draft, 1975 March 20 (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - Prospects for Increasing World Food Production - Ewell, 1975 April 14 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - A Strategy to Overcome World Hunger, World Agricultural Dilemmas, Sterling Wortman and Ralph W. Cummings, Jr, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - Puebla Project, 1975 April 29 (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - World Food Outlook - Cotton Outlook Conference, 1975 May 29 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Outlook and Prospects for Meeting World Food Needs - Western Agricultural Economics Association (WAEA), 1975 July 21 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Western Agricultural Economics Association (WAEA), 1975 July 20-22 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - The Role of Animals in the World Food Situation, 1975 October (Box 12, Folder 133)
  - The State of Present and Expected Technology and Agricultural Research on Livestock for the Low-Income Countries, 1976 March 2 (Box 12, Folder 134)
  - Easing the World Food Problem, Chicago, 1976 November 29 (Box 12, Folder 135)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Status of Technology - Food Crops, 1976 May (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - Defined Area Campaigns: Principles Underlying Implementation, 1977 April (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - Incoming Director's Report, Botswana, 1977 September 29 (Box 12, Folder 138)
  - Minimum Information Systems, Seminar Report, 1977 September (Box 12, Folder 139)
  - Marketing and Price Policy, Working Papers and Report, German Foundation for International Development, Feldafing, Germany, 1977 November (Box 12, Folder 140)
  - Land Tenure and Agricultural Development, 1978 July (Box 12, Folder 141)
    Written by Ralph Cummings, Jr. with staff from the University of Wisconsin Land Tenure Center
  - International Agricultural Development Service (IADS) - Agricultural Development Indicators: A Statistical Handbook, 1978; 1980; 1981 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - Planning and Implementing Research to Promote Accelerated Agricultural Development (With Special Emphasis on Small Farmers), Draft, 1978 October 5 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - World Games, 1979 July 20 (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - Agricultural Prices, Production and Growth, S K Ray, Ralph W Cummings, Jr and Robert W. Herdt, Reprint, 1979 September (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Feeding the World, Midwestern Conference on Food and Social Policy, Iowa, 1979 November 14 (Box 12, Folder 146)
  - Transmigration, 1981 September (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Targets for Agricultural Development in Botswana, Kristian Oland, Hoyt Alverson and Ralph Cummings, Jr, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - A Policy Strategy for Agricultural Development, 1979 May 14 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development - Development Assistance Committee - Workshop on Linkages Between Agricultural Research and Farmers in Developing Countries, 1981 June (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - North Carolina State Agricultural and Technical University Speech, The Dimension of World Hunger Problem and Strategies for Its Alleviation, 1981 October (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - To Feed This World, Indonesian, 1981 November (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - World Food Needs and Prospects, John A. Pino, Ralph W. Cummings, Jr and Gary H. Toenniessen, Reprint, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - Rural Development Paper, Rejected, 1982 October (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - A Policy Strategy for Agricultural Development, 1981 December 30 (Box 13, Folder 155)
  - Rajiv Gandhi Institute for Contemporary Studies (RGICS)-World Bank-International Food Policy Research Institute (IFPRI) Workshop on "Re-energizing Agriculture in India" Group Photo, New Delhi, 2004 December 17; 2017:025:023 (Box 20, Folder 242)
  - Miscellaneous, 1983; 2013 (Box 13, Folder 156)
    2013 article about Mali in the age of technology and correspondence related to the Agency Strategy Paper for Food and Agricultural Development Assistance
  - Honorary Citizen of the State of Alabama Certificate, 1983 February 14 (Box 13, Folder 157)
  - US Agency for International Development (USAID) Certificates, 1996; 2002 (Box 13, Folder 158)
    20 years of service award and group award for Greater Horn of Africa Initiative
  - Carter Center, 1997-1998 (Box 13, Folder 159)
  - World Food Summit, 1996-2002 (Box 13, Folder 160-161)
    - Group Holding Plaques photograph, undated; 2017:025:024 (Box 20, Folder 243)
      Group holding plaques (possibly Group Honor Award for Excellence, World Food Summit Preparatory Team)
  - Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR), 1992-1994 (Box 13, Folder 162-163)
    Includes drafts of reports: CGIAR Agricultural Research Priorities and The Future of AID Support to the CGIAR, correspondence regarding the budget and funding, visit to the International Center for the Improvement of Maize and Wheat (CIMMYT), and meeting with Ambassador Robert Blake and Dr. Jessica Tuchman Matthews
    - Group at Dinner photograph, undated; 2017:025:025 (Box 20, Folder 244)
  - Agribusiness: From Parastatals to Private Trade - Why, When, and How?, Final Panel Discussion - From Parastatals and Private Trade, New Delhi, 2003 December (Box 13, Folder 164)
    - International Workshop - Agribusiness: From Parastatals to Private Trade group photograph, New Delhi, 2003 December 15-16; 2017:025:026 (Box 20, Folder 245)
  - Extension, 1981-1985 (Box 13, Folder 165)
  - Strengthening Public Extension Systems, Draft, 1985 December 27 (Box 14, Folder 166)
  - US Agency for International Development (USAID), 1979-2009 (Box 14, Folder 167-173)
    Correpondence regarding finances and budget, reports on the Philippines and Africa, Conducting an Agricultural Assessment: A Framework for Strategy Development drafts, Advanced Developing Country (ADC) Concepts Paper, Vision Statement: AID Support for the International Agricultural Research Center System, and Is Aid Doing Enough to Promote Diffusion/Extension of Existing Agricultural Technology, and AID Agricultural Sector Guidance and Implementation draft
    - Untitled photographs, undated; 2017:025:027 (Box 20, Folder 246)
      3 unidentified photos - Ralph W. Cummings, Jr with unidentified man in front of mountains and 2 photos of people shaking hands
    - Untitled photographs, undated; 2017:025:028 (Box 20, Folder 247)
      5 unidentified photographs, including one black and white group photo
  - US Agency for International Development (USAID) - Revised Research Priority Implementation Plans, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 174)
  - A Symposium on World Hunger, Buffalo, 1983 October (Box 14, Folder 175)
  - Tuskegee Institute Small Farms Conference, 1983 February 13-15 (Box 14, Folder 176)
  - Research Priorities Rewrite - "Ten Commandments" for Land Settlement Development Projects, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 177)
  - Indonesia Research Agenda, 1984 November (Box 14, Folder 178)